# SHUBHAM GOYAL

# **Software Engineer**

@ shubhamgoyal7125@gmail.com 🗍 +91 8053889763 🖸 github.com/ShubhamGoyal7125 🛍 linkedin.com/in/shubham-goyal-7987461b8

% https://shubhamgoyal7125.github.io/Portfolio

# **EXPERIENCE**

Research Internship (under Dr. Ashish Payal)

#### **Guru Gobind Singh Indraprastha University**

## July 2022 - Sept 2022

P Delhi, India

• Made a Metaverse Ecommerce Mall with AR-VR and other functionalities using Mozilla Hubs, echo3D, and sketchFab.

## Full Stack Web Development Internship SDC-USICT, Guru Gobind Singh Indraprastha University

Ctober 2021 - November 2022

P Delhi, India

- Revamped the http://www.ipu.ac.in from scratch.
- · Made the official website of SDC-USICT.
- Currently, I am the web development team lead.
- Used PHP, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, and GitHub.

## Backend Developer Internship

## SalesCaptain (formerly SalesBook)

## July 2022 - August 2022

Remote

- Made API's for sending SMS and Email to customers using SendGrid and Twilio and stored the webhook data in MySQL.
- · Made API endpoints for making subscription plans and payment gateways for users using Chargebee and Stripe.
- · Used Node.js, Express.js, and Postman.

# **PROJECTS**

#### iNotebook [MERN]

**Source** 

**Demo** 

Create account then add, update and delete your notes.

Technologies used: React.js, Node.js, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, MongoDB, MongoDB Compass, Bootstrap, Vercel.

#### News-Daily [React.js, Node.js]

Get the daily news on different topics.

Technologies used: React.js, Node.js, HTML, CSS, JavaScript.

### To-Do List [Express.js, MongoDB]

#### **Source**

Make your own to-do list to remember all important tasks.

Technologies used: Express.js, Node.js, MongoDB, MongoDB Atlas, EJS, CSS, JavaScript, Heroku.

## **PROFILE**

I am a qualified and enthusiastic Software Development Engineer with experience of over 1.5 years in software design, development, testing, and strong creative skills. I am a team player with an eye for details and excellent interpersonal. communication, and document preparation skills.

## **EDUCATION**

B.Tech in Computer Science and Engineering

University School of Information, Communication and Technology (GGSIPU)

Dec 2020 - Present CGPA - 9.541 (4 Semesters)

School [Non-Medical] A. V. International Public School

2005 - 2020

12th Board -95.8%

10th Board - 95.6%

# SKILLS

- Languages: C, C++, JavaScript
- Full Stack Development: HTML5. CSS3, JavaScript, Express.js, Node.js, React.js, Rest APIs, Bootstrap, Tailwind, WordPress
- Database: SQL, MySQL, MongoDB, MongoDB Atlas, MongoDB Compass
- · General: DSA, OOPS. Problem-solving skills, Heroku, Vercel, Git, GitHub, Postman, Thunder Client, Linux, Windows
- Familiar: AWS, Google Cloud Platform, UI/UX,SEO, Stripe, TypeScript, Twilio, SendGrid, Chargebee, Java

# CERTIFICATIONS

Flipkart Grid 4.0 Hackathon

Google Cloud Program 2021